Guide to the Frederic O. Glover Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Frederic O. Glover papers
1929-1993
SC0468
Glover, Frederic O.
8 Linear feet
These personal papers of Frederic O. Glover pertain mostly to his writing and his interest in Stanford history; there are very few papers relating to his official activities as presidential aide. Included are oral history transcripts, correspondence, stories and articles, travel journals, speeches, class of 1933 reunion files, subject files, and photographs.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Frederic Glover, 1992, and estate of Frederick Glover, 1994.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Frederic O. Glover enjoyed a long association with Stanford University. A member of the class of 1933, Glover returned to Stanford in 1946 as its first full-time director of information. In 1952 he moved to the President's office as assistant to President J.E. Wallace Sterling and was promoted in 1959 to executive assistant. He remained in the President's office under President Kenneth Pitzer, 1968-70, and then was appointed secretary to the university by President Richard W. Lyman. Glover retired in 1977 but remained active at Stanford as a founding member of the Stanford Historical Society and a member of the Stanford Associates. He also started the Stanford Oral History Project, a joint effort of the Stanford Historical Society and the Stanford University Archives. Fred Glover died of cancer on November 18, 1993.
Description of the Collection
These personal papers of Frederic O. Glover pertain mostly to his writing and his interest in Stanford history; there are very few papers relating to his official activities as presidential aide. Included are oral history transcripts, correspondence, stories and articles, travel journals, speeches, class of 1933 reunion files, subject files, and photographs.
Access Terms
Glover, Frederic O.; Stanford Oral History Project.; Stanford University -- General subdivision--History.;; Stanford University. Class of 1933.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Oral History - Forms, etc. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Oral History (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Oral History: Roth, Almon E. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Oral History: Jacobson, David S. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Class of 1933 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Class of 1933 - 50th Reunion (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Class of 1933 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Stanford History I (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Stanford History II (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Stanford University: 1947 - 1952 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Stanford University: 1967 - 1977 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Stanford University: 1978 - 1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Stanford University: 1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Stanford University: 1979 - 1992 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Stanford University: 1982 - 1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: 1929 - 1988 (Montezuma High School & FBI) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: 1978 - 1992 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Brown (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Verleye, Karel J. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Stanford-in-Florence with Story (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Stanford-in-England with Story (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Stanford-in-Vienna with Story (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Stanford-in-Paris with Story (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Stanford-in-Tours with Story (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Stanford-in-Berlin with Story (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Stanford: Germany & Europe, 1958-1960 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Europe - England (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Europe: Italy, Oct. 1977 - April 1978 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Germany (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Europe: French Talks (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Europe: May, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Europe: Salzburg Seminars (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Eastern (U.S.) trip, 9/22/83 - 10/13/83 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Walker Dinner Slide Show, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Articles: A - B (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Articles: C - E (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Articles: F - G (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Articles: M - Q (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Articles: S (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Articles: T (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Article: "Judy - The Pet Gopher" (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Article: "Daring Young Men & Balloons," (a) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Article: "Daring Young Men & Balloons," (b) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Writings: Autobiography (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Biographical Information (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Speeches and Talks: Stanford History (Slide Show) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Speeches and Talks: Alumni Association Speech - 5/11/62 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Speeches and Talks: Shelter Talk (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Sterling Family (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Sterling Family (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Sterling (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Sterling (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Lyman, Richard and Jing (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Terman, Frederick E. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Gardner, John: Common Cause (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Memorial Service: Birge Clark (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Memorial Service: David Mason (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Memorial Service: Ernest and Katherine Arbuckle (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Obituary: Fred Glover, Jr. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Stanford Campus: Rediscover Stanford Campus Bus Tour, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Campus: Info. on Stanford Gardens (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Campus: Ronald Bracewell -- Tree Walk (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Campus: Stanford Family Statue (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Campus: Meyer-Buck House (7/81) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Associates (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Partisan Politics at Stanford (a) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Partisan Politics at Stanford (b) (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Delta Tau Delta (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Diplomas (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Clippings (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Stanford History (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Class of 1960: 20th Reunion (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Photographs:
    - 1933 Boxing Champs, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Frat House: Delt House (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - L. H. Hoover House; Hanna House (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Fred G. & Official S.U. Functions (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Fred: S.U. Work (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Class of 1933 Reunion (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Cornerstone Centennial 1987 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Delt House after Fire 1991 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Founders Day 1990; Gold Spike Dinner 1992 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Founders Day 1993 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Gold Spike Lunch 1991 (Sacramento) (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Various S.U. Events (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - S.U Campus (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - C.B. Thornton ground Breaking (S.U.?) (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - G. Casper's Inaugeration (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - 1991 Opening Day Centennial Ceremony (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Centennial Celebration 11/11/85 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Bracelet made for Mrs. Glover (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Fred Glover, informal (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Unsorted: Personal photographs (Box 8)
  - Unsorted: Personal photographs (Box 9)
  - Slides (Box 10)
  - Negatives (Box 11)
  - Class of 1933: 50th Reunion (Box 12 os)
  - Trustees Manual 1978 (Box 12 os)
  - Diplomas and Awards (Box 13 os)
  - Awards and miscellaneous items (Box 14 os)